[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[저작권 보호는 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
[Episode 24]
[제24화]
Master is at Hushe Peak.
'사부님은 호사에 계시다'
Jiaping's distant-sensing talisman?
대사형의 요지부다
He's in danger.
대사형께 변고가 생겼어
Jiaping?
대사형?
Have you found him?
그분을 찾았어?
Where is Hushe?
호사는 어디냐?
What happened?
무슨 일이 벌어진 거냐?
It's Hushe Peak, the secret forbidden area of Wuyue Court.
호사봉, 무월정의 비경금지오
I'll go back with you.
내가 함께 돌아가겠다
My Lord.
존상님
Rakshasa.
나찰
You finally remember me, My Lord.
존상님, 드디어 저를 기억해 주시네요
You slew Zong Quan
이번에 존상님께서 종권을 죽여
and rid the demon clan of Longming Sanctuary.
마족을 위해 용명좌를 없애 주셨으니
Truly a joyous victory!
정말 축하드릴 일입니다
Through the chaos in the Yue State,
이번 월국의 난을 통해
you've seen clearly
존상님께서는 선문 사람들의
the shameless faces of all immortal sects.
그 더러운 본색을 똑똑히 보셨지요
What's the difference between the immortal sects or the demon clan?
선문이든 마족이든 무슨 상관이랴
All schemes for petty self-interest.
모두 사사로운 이익을 위해 꾀를 부릴 뿐
I ordered you to return. Why didn't you?
내가 돌아가라 명했거늘 왜 돌아가지 않았느냐?
Five centuries ago, we crossed the East Sea.
오백 년 전 제가 존상님을 모시고 동도했을 때
You said back then
존상님께서는
this would be our new home.
여기가 바로 우리의 새로운 고향이라 말씀하셨습니다
Have you forgotten?
잊으셨습니까?
Now I'm reborn as a mortal.
이미 인간으로 환생했으니
All the past means nothing to me.
예전의 일들은 나와 상관이 없다
I came to you for another matter.
나는 다른 일로 너를 불렀다
Lifei and I are going to Hushe Peak.
나와 려비는 호사봉으로 들어갈 것이다
Jiang Lifei again.
또 강려비라고요?
She is merely an ordinary woman.
그녀는 평범한 여자일 뿐이고
You are the great Demon Lord.
존상님은 당당한 마군이신데
Would you abandon your grand cause
그녀를 위해 대업을 버리고
and sink low for her?
왜 스스로 타락하려 하십니까?
You keep addressing me as My Lord,
말로만 존상이라 부르지
yet you act on your own
번번이 멋대로 결정하고
and question every choice I make.
내 결정에 간섭하다니
Do you expect me to obey you instead?
혹시 내가 너를 따르게 하려는 것이냐?
I... I dare not.
제가 어찌 감히 그러겠습니까?
You came back, after all.
결국 돌아왔군
Master, I wish to borrow the Hexagonal Prism.
사부님, 육능경을 빌리고 싶습니다
I fear once you uncover the truth you seek,
네가 찾으려는 진실을 알고 나면
you'll sink into mire with no escape.
진흙 구덩이에 빠져 헤매지 못할 것이다
My senior brother
대사형과
and the old man who raised me
저를 키워주신 그 영감도
must be waiting for me.
분명 저를 기다리고 계실 겁니다
Lifei, we shall be master and disciple for all time.
려비, 우리는 평생 사부제자 사이니
Zhuiyu Peak will always be your home.
추옥봉도 언제나 너의 집이다
Go.
가라
♪With you, we climb bleak cliffs beneath endless gloom♪
♪너와 함께 험한 바위를 오르며 하늘은 보이지 않고♪
♪Bow our heads and endure bitter gales♪
♪고개 숙여 거친 바람을 마시리♪
♪Ambition surges; we hold new feasts amid thorns♪
♪웅장한 뜻이 일어나 가시밭에서 다시 잔치를 열리♪
♪Let frost, snow and rain block the long stone steps♪
♪서리와 비바람이 이 기나긴 계단을 가로막을지라도♪
♪I tread fleeting mist beneath my feet♪
♪발아래의 고난을 연기처럼 밟고 나아가리♪
♪At last I see, life's end lies boundless wild free♪
♪마침내 깨닫네, 인생의 끝은 광야임을♪
♪Don't idle away time. We shall meet atop the peak♪
♪헛되이 세월을 보내지 말자, 우리는 반드시 정상에서 만나리♪
Yangling, that's the direction of Wengu Hall.
사형, 문고전 방향입니다
It's demonic energy! Go.
마기다, 가자
Why is the maple forest stretching further?
풍림이 왜 더 커졌지?
You're too hasty and fell for an illusion.
네가 너무 조급하여 환술에 속은 거야
Are we at home?
집으로 돌아왔네
No, we're still on Hushe Peak.
아니, 아직 호사봉 안이야
Watch out!
조심해
Where are we?
여긴 어디야?
I've heard that when immortal cultivators reach a certain realm,
선문의 고수들의 수위가 일정한 경지에 오르면
they can open
그들만의
a private world of their own,
세계를 펼친다고 들었어
complete with mountains, rivers, sun, moon, and boundless clouds.
산하일월, 천운만해
They set all the laws
이 세계의 규칙은
governing this realm,
본인이 만들고 속박하는 거야
which is known as a miniature realm.
이런 세계를 소천세계라고 불러
Whose
그럼
miniature realm is this?
여긴 누구의 소천세계지?
It's Cuihua Peak's restriction spell.
취화봉의 금제다
This must be Cuixuan's miniature realm.
여긴 아마도 취현의 소천세계일 것이야
Where's the Hexagonal Prism?
사숙께서 네게 준 육능경은?
Go.
가자
Didn't expect Cuixuan's miniature realm
취현의 소천세계가
to have such thick spirit energy.
이토록 영기가 풍부한 곳일 줄이야
Is this Hushe Peak's secret?
설마 여기가 바로 호사봉의 비밀인가?
What's up?
왜 그래?
I sensed weird energy all around.
이곳에서 이상한 기식이 느껴져
Feels like demonic energy, but not quite.
마기인 것 같은데 달라
Why would demonic energy exist in an immortal secret land?
선문 비경에 어찌 마기가 흐를까?
Flowers growing out of skeletons.
백골생화
They live off demonic energy
마기와 원령을 양분으로
and vengeful spirits.
피어난 꽃이야
The more hatred, the brighter the flowers.
원념이 깊을수록 더욱 선명하게 피지
Their roots trap
이 뿌리들은
lost, unwilling souls
그 억울한 혼령들을
in dirty mud,
더러운 흙 속에 가두어
with no escape forever.
영원히 벗어나지 못하게 하지
All these demon bones
이 마골들은
had their power sucked dry when they lived.
생전에 영기를 모조리 빨려 나갔었어
Is this Zong Quan's Spirit-Devouring Art?
종권의 서령사법인가?
No, it's Wuyue Court's Spirit-Binding Art,
아니, 무월정의 봉령의 술법이야
same as the binding barrier of Lilie Valley.
열렬곡의 금고결계와 비슷하지
You mean Cuixuan's trained by using demon spirits?
그러니까 취현이 계속 마령으로 수련했다는 거야?
Human hearts carry dark schemes.
인심귀역이군
What's the difference between the immortal sects or the demon clan?
선문과 마족이 무슨 차이가 있단 말이냐
Calm down. Don't turn into a Yecha.
수원, 진정해, 야차로 변하지 마
I'm fine.
괜찮아
No aura here.
여긴 이제 기식이 하나도 없어
No traces of living things are left here. Let's leave.
살아있는 생령이 없으니까 가자
Wait.
아니야
There's a faint aura lingering.
한 가닥 기식이 남아 있어
Who are you?
누구세요?
The spirit energy doesn't work at all, Xiuyuan.
왜 영기가 통하지 않지?
His heart meridians are severed.
심맥이 끊어져
He won't make it.
살지 못할 거야
No.
아닐 거야
As long as he is alive, there will be hope.
살아있다면 분명 방도가 있을 거야
Lifei.
려비
Sir, hold on.
어르신, 조금만 버티십시오
I'll get you out of here.
제가 바로 모시고 나가겠습니다
Don't move.
움직이지 마
How could this happen?
어찌 이런 일이...
Qingcheng.
청성
Go.
가라
Master.
사부님
Lifei.
려비
Go.
가라
- Let's get out of here. - No!
- 나가자 - 싫어
No! Master!
싫다고, 사부님
Don't leave me!
저를 버리지 마세요
Master! Master!
사부님
- Master! - Lifei.
- 사부님 - 려비
Master!
사부님
Qingcheng!
사형
Foolish brats, how dare you ruin my secret realm!
무식한 놈들, 감히 본좌의 비경을 망가뜨려?
So this is indeed your miniature realm.
역시 네놈의 소천세계였구나
It's you! You killed him.
네가 사부님을 죽였어
You killed my master!
네가 내 사부님을 죽였어
Your master?
네 사부라고?
I'll kill you!
죽여버릴 거야
Lifei!
려비
Demons.
마족
They're demon spies. Seize them!
저들은 마족의 세작들이다, 잡아라
Jiang Lifei, Lei Xiuyuan, you have nowhere to run.
강려비, 뇌수원, 너희는 도망칠 수 없을 거다
Dead as you are,
죽으면 그만이지
your remnants still dare stir trouble.
잔당을 남겨 소란을 피우다니
Do you think destroying my miniature realm
제 소천세계를 망가뜨리고
and crippling my spirit roots can stop me?
제 영근을 훼손했다 해서 저를 막을 거라 생각합니까?
Listen!
알려주는데
That girl is your disciple.
그 계집애가 사형의 제자라면
The Senluo Grand Art must be on her.
삼라대법도 분명 그녀가 갖고 있겠지요
Qingcheng, be patient.
사형, 급해 마십시오
I'll bring her back soon.
제가 곧 그녀를 데려올 겁니다
Once I fetch her,
그녀를 데려온 뒤
you can reunite with her.
빨리 사형과 다시 만나게 해줄게요
Zhaomin, what are you doing here?
소민 사매, 네가 왜 여기 있어?
Qin.
진 사형
I should be asking you the same.
오히려 사형은 왜 여기에 있는 겁니까?
This is near Zhuiyu Peak.
여긴 추옥봉 근처잖아요
Where did you come from?
어디서 튀어나오신 거예요?
You nearly scared Zhaomin.
소민 사저가 놀랐잖아요
I was ordered to capture demon spies.
나는 마족 세작을 잡으러 왔다
Demon spies?
마족 세작이요?
Where?
어디에 있는데요?
Where are they?
어디에 있냐고요?
She and I?
설마 저희요?
No.
아니
We only planned
저희는 그저
to pick fresh morning herbs together.
새벽 약초를 캐러 온 것뿐인데
Why call us spies, Yangling?
어찌 사형 눈엔 세작으로 보인단 말입니까?
What's your deal?
무슨 뜻입니까?
Who said you're demon spies?
누가 너희를 세작이라 하였나?
You just said it, right?
방금 사형이 그랬잖아요, 그렇죠?
You heard clearly, huh?
사저도 들었죠?
Yangling,
사형
do you think everyone's a spy?
누구나 다 세작으로 보이는 겁니까?
You even accused Lifei before.
전에는 려비 사매가 세작이라면서요
I know the truth.
알겠다
She rejected you,
사매한테 거절당한 뒤 그녀가 잘되는 걸
so you're jealous of her.
보지 못하는 거네요
You!
너...
Can't believe you struck out!
사형, 왜 손까지 쓰고 그러십니까?
Zhaomin, back me up.
소민 사저, 증인이 되어 주세요
He threw the first punch.
사형이 먼저 손을 쓴 겁니다
I won't back down from a fight.
저 등계광은 죽는 게 두렵지 않거든요
Come on, let's settle this.
한번 겨뤄 볼까요?
Don't run. Let's go to Cuixuan...
사형, 잠깐만요, 취현 찾으러 가요...
Stop pretending. Go check how they are.
연기 그만하고 빨리 그들 살피러 가자
Are you okay? Bad injuries?
어때, 많이 다쳤어?
We're fine. Why are you here?
괜찮습니다, 사저께서는 어떻게 오셨습니까?
Master noticed the Hexagonal Prism went haywire
사부님께서 육능경의 이상을 발견하고
and sent us to help you.
너를 도우라고 우릴 보냈다
Tell him I'm thankful.
대신 고맙다고 전해주세요
What happened last night could get him into trouble.
어젯밤의 일은 사부님께도 피해가 갈 텐데
It's fine. He knows how to handle it.
괜찮다, 사부님께서는 대응할 방도가 있을 거다
But look, it's daytime now.
너희들이야말로 날도 밝았고
The whole sect is under strict guard.
문파 각 곳도 경비가 삼엄한데
How will you escape?
어떻게 도망쳐 나갈 것이야?
Don't worry. I know a hidden path in the mountains.
걱정 마, 내가 아는 밀도가 있어
You can leave without being noticed.
아무도 모르게 빠져나갈 수 있을 거다
No more delays, let's go.
더 이상 지체하지 말고 빨리 가자
Watch your step.
조심
- Stay safe, Lifei. - This way.
- 사매야, 조심해야 한다 - 따라와
Hurry up.
얼른
That's impossible.
말도 안 됩니다
Xiuyuan is quiet and stubborn,
수원은 비록 고집스럽지만
but he always respects his masters and behaves properly.
언제나 사부를 공경하고 이치를 아는 자니
He's never done anything to betray the sect.
절대 선문을 거스르지 않을 겁니다
Cuixuan, you said they're demon spies.
사형, 그들이 마족의 세작이라는데
Got any proof?
증거는 있습니까?
Lei Xiuyuan and Jiang Lifei snuck into the forbidden area at night,
뇌수원, 강려비가 밤중에 금지에 쳐들어왔고
releasing demonic energy.
마기를 품고 있었다
If they aren't spies, how can they use demonic arts?
마족의 세작이 아니라면 왜 마공을 쓰겠느냐?
As to what happened at Lilie Valley last time,
이제 보니 저번 열렬곡 사건도
they must be guilty.
그들에게 혐의가 있구나
Cuixuan,
사형
you personally chose
당시 정예 제자들을 뽑아
those top disciples
곡 안으로 보내 결계를 수리하게 한 것도
to fix the valley barrier back then.
사형의 결정이었잖아요
Yes.
맞습니다
They had injuries all over them,
그 두 아이가 상처를 입고 있었는데
but you forced them to go.
사형이 억지로 보내셨잖아요
I tried talking you out of it, but failed.
제가 말렸지만 듣지도 않으셨고
As for the demonic energy on them,
마기를 품고 있는 건
they probably got tainted
마족들과 싸울 때
when fighting demons.
부주의하게 마기에 침식된 것이겠죠
Cuixuan, what's hidden
사형, 호사봉의 금지에
in Hushe Peak's forbidden area?
대체 무엇을 숨기신 겁니까?
Don't you know
왜 호사봉을 봉인했는지
why I lock Hushe Peak up?
설마 모르고 있느냐?
I know well if someone's
마기에 침식됐는지 마공을 수련했는지
tainted or using demonic arts.
본좌가 몰라서
I wouldn't frame them.
그들을 억울하게 몰아세웠단 말이냐?
Easy there, Cuixuan.
사형, 노여움을 푸십시오
Chongyi
충이 사형도
only wants what's best for Wuyue Court.
무월정을 위한 것입니다
This must be a misunderstanding, I think.
중간에 오해가 있는 거 아닙니까?
Misunderstanding?
오해는 무슨
Jiang Lifei is always stirring up trouble.
네 제자는 문제 덩어리다
I bet she dragged Xiuyuan into all this.
이번에도 분명 네 제자가 수원을 홀렸을 것이다
Nonsense!
말도 안 돼
Lei Xiuyuan lured her instead!
분명 사형 제자가 제 제자를 유혼한 거잖아요
I'm still mad thinking about it.
생각해 보니 화가 나네
Last time in Duantu,
저번에 단도에서
Jiang Lifei was weak,
제 제자가 몸이 허약한 틈을 타
and Lei Xiuyuan actually...
그가 감히...
I don't even want to say it out loud.
말하기조차 부끄럽군
Cuixuan, your aura is unstable.
사형, 기식이 안정되지 않습니다
Looks like your spirit energy backfired on you.
영기가 역으로 덮친 것 같습니다
Did you get hurt?
혹시 다치셨습니까?
Those two spies ambushed me.
그 두 세작이 날 습격해서다
I let my guard slip, but I'm fine.
내가 방심한 탓이지만 큰 지장은 없다
Brief meditation is enough.
휴식을 취하면 회복될 것이다
It's simply out of line!
정말 말도 안 돼
I mean Lifei and Xiuyuan.
그 두 아이 말입니다
Cuixuan, take care.
사형, 편안히 수양하십시오
I'll fetch them back right now.
제가 지금 그들을 찾아오겠습니다
Don't worry.
걱정 마세요
Chongyi, I'll come with you.
사제야, 내가 같이 가겠다
Xiaobangchui, what are you doing at the door?
소봉추, 뭐 하느냐?
Put medicine on my injuries and wrap them.
얼른 와서 사부 상처에 약 바르고 붕대 감아라
Master,
사부님
you must've waited for me so long.
저를 오래 기다리셨죠
I finally found you.
드디어 찾았네요
I finally
드디어
found you.
찾았네요
Go ahead and cry if you want to.
울고 싶으면 울어
Master didn't like seeing me cry.
사부님께서는 내가 우는 걸 싫어하셨어
I'll hold it in.
나 잘 지낼 거야
I won't make him fret over me.
사부님께 걱정 끼치지 않게
I'll grab some food.
내가 먹을 것을 가져올게
As the Demon Lord, you'd let a woman order you around.
당당한 마존이 여자에게 끌려다니다니
My Lord,
존상님
Jiang Lifei is the Divine Tree, right?
강려비가 바로 건목이죠?
Blame me for being blind
제가 눈이 어두워
to her true identity.
일찍 알아보지 못했습니다
Then again,
하긴
every Demon Lord ends up falling for the Divine Tree.
역대 마군들은 모두 건목을 사랑했습니다
This is our chance to restore the demon clan.
이것이 바로 마족이 다시 일어날 기회입니다
When are you going to absorb her spirit power?
존상께서는 언제 그녀의 영력을 흡수하실 겁니까?
Leave her alone.
멀리 떨어져라
Did you forget you're Yecha?
존상께서는 본인이 야차인 걸 잊으셨습니까?
For hundreds of years,
천백 년 동안
no Demon Lord
어느 한 마군도
has broken this curse.
저주받은 운명을 피하지 못했습니다
No matter how dedicated
아무리 애를 쓰시고
or loving you are,
정이 깊다고 해도
the Fruit of the Divine Tree
건목은 존상한테는
will lure you without fail.
저항할 수 없는 유혹입니다
It's just your nature as Yecha.
이게 바로 야차의 본능입니다
If you can't bear to do it yourself,
존상께서 직접 손대기 힘드시다면
I'll handle it for you.
제가 대신 처리하겠습니다
My Lord,
존상님
are you really going to kill me?
정말 저를 죽이실 겁니까?
After the heaven's wrath, spirit energy grew scarce on the islands,
천벌 이후 천주만도의 영기가 희박해져
and our clansmen could barely survive.
족인들은 살아남지 못합니다
You promised
존상께서
you'd take us back to the Central Plains,
족인들은 살아남기 위해 중토로
so we could survive.
돌아가야 한다고 하셨습니다
Five centuries ago, after you disappeared,
오백 년 전 존상께서 실종된 후
the immortal sects hunted our clansmen down.
선문은 우리 일족을 무차별 학살했습니다
We were almost wiped out.
거의 전명하다시피 했죠
My Lord, only by absorbing the Divine Tree's power
존상님, 건목을 흡수해야만
can you gain your Yecha power
야차의 힘을 얻으실 수 있고
and find our clansmen a way out.
우리 일족에게 살길을 열 수 있습니다
I live only for you and our clansmen,
저는 오직 존상과 일족을 위해 살았습니다
at all costs, without regret.
백번 죽어도 후회 없습니다
But snap out of it, My Lord.
하지만 존상님께서 빨리 정신을 차리시고
Save our dying clansmen.
죽어가는 우리 일족을 구해주십시오
My Lord.
존상님
You're badly hurt.
중상을 입으셔서
If you don't absorb the Divine Tree's power, your soul will split apart,
건목을 흡수하지 않으면 영혼이 찢어지고
and you'll die in terrible pain.
고통 속에서 죽게 될 겁니다
I know my own fate!
내 목숨은 내가 잘 알고 있다
If you touch her even once,
네가 그녀를 건들기만 하면
no matter what you've done for me,
네가 전에 무슨 일을 했든
I'll kill you.
나는 꼭 너를 죽일 것이다
I've always been ready to die
저는 언제든지 존상을 위해
for you at all times. But what about her?
죽을 각오가 되어있습니다, 하지만 그녀는요?
Are you going to abandon all of us
정말 그녀를 위해 전족을 배신하고
and risk your life for her?
목숨까지 버리실 겁니까?
I'm Lei Xiuyuan.
나는 뇌수원이다
Nothing will ever change that.
평생 오직 뇌수원일 것이다
My Lord.
존상님
My Lord, don't blame me.
존상님, 저를 원망하지 마십시오
All is for our clan's future.
모든 건 우리 일족의 대업을 위해서입니다
Lifei, eat something.
려비, 뭐라도 좀 먹어
I'm okay.
괜찮아
I wished to burn
사부님께
fine robes for Master,
좋은 옷을 찾아서 태워드리려는데
yet all are ragged.
전부 낡고 찢어졌더라
His final robes were tattered
사부께서 입으셨던 마지막 옷도
beyond recognition.
알아보기 힘들 정도로 찢어졌어
Lifei,
려비
that strap.
저 끈...
Master left it for me.
사부님께서 이걸 남겨주신 건
There must be a story behind it.
분명 이유가 있을 거야
Why's there nothing on it?
왜 전부 비어 있을까?
Master, what did you want me to know?
사부님께서 대체 무엇을 전하시려는 거지?
Xiuyuan, check this with me.
수원, 좀 봐줘
Xiuyuan!
수원
Come out! We saw you.
나와라, 내가 다 봤다
You have no place to run.
너희는 도망칠 수 없을 거다
Guangwei and I are here for you two.
내가 너희 광미 사백과 함께 찾으러 왔다
Only he and I,
우리 둘뿐이다
but you can't get away.
그래도 너희는 도망칠 수 없을 거다
Wait, this place reeks of heavy toxic mist.
아니다, 여기 장기가 이렇게 짙은데
Nobody could stay here.
사람이 살 곳이 안 되지
That way, go.
저쪽으로 가지요
This place is even worse.
저쪽보다 더 못하군
Let's go back there.
다시 돌아가지요
Which path? We've wandered all night.
대체 어디로 가야 한단 말이냐?
You've been looping around, huh?
계속 제자리를 돌고 있잖아
Guangwei, don't lose your temper.
광 씨, 또 화났습니까?
Calm down. Here is the case.
화 푸시오, 그게
Look, Qingqiu is huge,
청구가 너무 크고
plus this heavy toxic fog.
장기가 이렇게 짙은데
It messes up our spirit energy,
우리 영력에 영향도 가니까
so it's normal to get lost.
길을 잃을 수도 있잖아요
Are you here to track them,
사람 찾으러 온 것이냐
or sneak them a warning?
아니면 소식을 전하러 온 것이냐?
What are you saying?
그게 무슨 말입니까?
I'm obviously here to track them.
당연히 사람 찾으러 온 거지
Never mind, I'll look by myself.
됐다, 나 혼자서 찾겠다
Alright, you lead.
네, 사형이 길을 잡으세요
Watch out. Don't fall into the ditch.
천천히 가시오, 구덩이에 빠지지 말고
Xiuyuan, hang in there.
수원, 조금만 버텨
The Ganhua Realm saved you last time.
저번에 감화지경에서 너를 구했었으니
It'll help you again.
이번에도 구할 수 있을 거야
No matter how dedicated
아무리 애를 쓰시고
or loving you are,
정이 깊다고 해도
you'll absorb the Divine Tree's power.
결국엔 건목을 흡수하게 될 겁니다
What's wrong? Feeling sick?
왜 그래, 어디 불편해?
Xiuyuan.
수원
I'm okay. Don't come close.
나 괜찮아, 오지 마
Is your injury hurting? Let me check.
상처가 심해진 거야? 보여줘
Stay away from me.
가까이 오지 마
Lei Xiuyuan, are you crazy?
뇌수원, 미쳤어?
You never mentioned your bad injuries.
그렇게 심하게 다쳤는데 말도 안 하고
Now you're pushing me away.
이제 와서 나한테 삐지고
If something bad happens to you...
만약 너한테 무슨 일이라도 생기면...
Listen up,
분명히 말하는데
I'd rather die than let you die.
내가 죽는 한이 있어도 너는 안 돼
All of you
너희 모두
must live.
죽으면 안 돼
No one's dying!
죽지 마
Lifei.
려비
♪The warmth within my arms♪
♪품 안에 가득했던 그대의 온기♪
♪I can no longer hold on to♪
♪내 이제는 끝내 붙잡지 못하네♪
♪In the cold night, how can I♪
♪시린 이 겨울밤, 그대를 어떻게 다시♪
♪Keep you warm until sunrise?♪
♪동이 틀 때까지 따스하게 품어줄까♪
♪My heartbeat freezes♪
♪가슴은 차갑게 얼어붙고♪
♪I can no longer tell you♪
♪마음을 전할 길조차 없는데♪
♪Looking you in the eyes, I cannot♪
♪그대 눈을 보며 하려던 그 한마디♪
Don't push me away.
더 이상 날 밀어내지 마
♪Utter that line♪
♪끝내 입 밖으로 내지 못하네♪
♪Knowing right and wrong♪
♪옳고 그름도, 흑백의 경계도♪
I know nothing.
난 아무것도 몰랐어
♪Black and gray are all illusions♪
♪검고 흐린 세상사 모두 부질없거늘♪
You never tell me about your injuries,
다쳐도 알려주지 않고
or when something goes wrong.
일이 생겨도 알려주지 않고
♪You're still screaming♪
♪그대는 여전히 목 놓아 울부짖으며♪
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪미련 없이 거칠게 발버둥 치는구나♪
You'd keep it a secret even if you died.
죽어도 알려주지 않고
I just...
내가...
♪The storm looms, yet the wind stands in its way♪
♪몰아치는 비바람 온몸으로 막아서며♪
I'm right there,
분명 가까이에 있었는데
yet I know nothing.
아무것도 몰랐어
♪Leaping straight into that heartbreaking past♪
♪내 기꺼이 이 몸을 던지리라 살을 도려내는 듯한 아픈 기억 속으로♪
What do you want me to do?
대체 어떻게 하길 바라?
♪Just to keep you safe♪
♪그대만 무사할 수 있다면♪
What should I do?
나 어떻게 해야 해?
♪My breath is about to stop♪
♪내 숨결이 점차 희미해지고♪
♪Those hands can no longer hold yours♪
♪맞잡은 그 손을 더는 쥘 수 없으니♪
♪Through the future snow, wind, and fog♪
♪앞으로 다가올 시린 바람과 안개를♪
♪Who will be there by your side?♪
♪이제 누구와 함께 견뎌내야 할까♪
♪I smile as it ends♪
♪미소를 지으며 눈을 감는 것은♪
♪Afraid that you might cry for me♪
♪나로 인해 그대 슬피 울까 염려되어♪
♪Quietly, I turn into a sky lantern♪
♪말없이 공명등 한 줄기 빛이 되어♪
♪To light your way through the night♪
♪그대가 걷는 어두운 밤길을 비추어 주리♪
♪Knowing right and wrong♪
♪옳고 그름도, 흑백의 경계도♪
♪Black and gray are all illusions♪
♪검고 흐린 세상사 모두 부질없거늘♪
Wait. What's wrong?
이상해, 어떻게 된 거지?
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪미련 없이 거칠게 발버둥 치는구나♪
♪The storm looms, yet the wind stands in its way♪
♪몰아치는 비바람 온몸으로 막아서며♪
♪A final farewell left on the cliff♪
♪절벽 끝자락에 눈물로 새긴 서약♪
♪I'd shatter my soul♪
♪살을 도려내는 듯한 아픔으로♪
♪To lay all your days in peace♪
♪남은 그대의 인생이 부디 평탄하기를♪
♪Who says that love and hate♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가 밀려와♪
Xiuyuan.
수원
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪차마 막을 수 없음을 누가 알랴♪
♪I will level the seas and mountains♪
♪내 저 산과 바다를 평정하고♪
How could this happen?
왜 이러지?
♪Break the waves, no matter how mad it seems♪
♪풍랑이 미쳐 날뛴대도 두렵지가 않네♪
♪The storm looms, yet I stand in its way♪
♪닥쳐오는 비바람을 내 기어이 가로막으리♪
Anyone infected by Soul-Bewitching Vines becomes bloodthirsty and violent,
미혼만에 걸린 사람들은 싸우기를 좋아하게 되고
no longer like themselves.
본성을 잃게 되지
My Lord, is the Divine Tree worth it?
존상님, 건목한테 이럴 가치가 있나요?
♪With the light from my fingertips, I build a paradise♪
♪내 손끝에 맺힌 마지막 빛으로 그대와 함께할 낙원을 세워♪
♪To wander with you♪
♪영원히 그대 곁을 거닐고 싶어라♪
He was badly hurt by Cuixuan, plus he's fighting the curse,
그는 취현에게 중상을 입고 저주까지 막아내느라
so his spirit meridians are messed up, and his soul is injured.
영맥이 어지럽고 혼백까지 손상됐다
What are you talking about?
무슨 말입니까?
Yue, who are you really?
악 사저, 대체 누구신가요?
I'm Rakshasa, the demon clan's Guardian.
나는 마족 호법, 나찰이다
In primordial times, ancient gods cursed the Yecha clan.
상고 때 야차 일족은 고신의 저주를 받았었다
If they don't absorb the Divine Tree's purest spirit power,
건목의 지순영력을 흡수하지 않으면
they'll go wild, lose their minds, and die from madness.
수화되어 이성을 잃고 광기에 휩싸이다 쇠약해 죽을 것이다
The seal holding back his curse is gone now,
존상님의 봉인은 이제 해제되었고
and his heart meridians are broken too.
게다가 심맥까지 손상되었으니
The curse hits way harder than before.
저주의 힘은 예전보다 더 강해졌다
If he keeps fighting it,
만약 계속 거부한다면
the curse will turn on him
저주가 역으로 덮쳐
and kill him.
결국 죽게 될 것이다
Jiang Lifei, only you can save him.
강려비, 너만 그를 구할 수 있다
How do I save him?
어떻게 구해야 하나요?
Every Demon Lord falls for the Divine Tree in every life.
역대 마존들은 건목을 사랑하게 되지
And every Divine Tree
그리고 역대의 건목은
gives herself up without hesitation.
기꺼이 자신을 바쳤었지
The Yecha clan has taken countless lives.
야차 일족은 살해한 업이 깊어
Life after life, you have to find the Fruit of the Divine Tree,
생사를 거듭하며 건목을 찾아가
eat its flesh, and take its power to calm the curse's hatred.
그 살과 피를 먹고 영력을 삼켜 주원을 풀어야 한다
If you don't, your souls will split apart,
그렇지 않으면 혼이 찢어지는 고통을 겪고
and you'll turn savage and die,
수화한 채 죽고
never escaping suffering.
영원히 구원받지 못할 것이다
Quit fighting it. It won't work.
더 이상 저항하지 마, 소용없어
Stop when you still can.
더는 잘못된 길로 가지 마
Bloodthirsty, eating flesh, and suffering forever.
살과 피를 먹고, 영원히 벗어날 수 없다고요?
If you really love him,
만약 정말 그를 사랑한다면
I'm sure
너도
you'll do what all the others did.
그녀들과 같은 선택을 할 거라 믿는다
I'm going to decoct medicinal herbs.
약을 달여 올게요
Aren't you going to save him?
그를 구하지 않을 거냐?
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
♪The warmth within my arms♪
♪품 안에 가득했던 그대의 온기♪
♪I can no longer hold on to♪
♪내 이제는 끝내 붙잡지 못하네♪
♪In the cold night, how can I♪
♪시린 이 겨울밤, 그대를 어떻게 다시♪
♪Keep you warm until sunrise?♪
♪동이 틀 때까지 따스하게 품어줄까♪
♪My heartbeat freezes♪
♪가슴은 차갑게 얼어붙고♪
♪I can no longer tell you♪
♪마음을 전할 길조차 없는데♪
♪Looking you in the eyes, I cannot♪
♪그대 눈을 보며 하려던 그 한마디♪
♪Utter that line♪
♪끝내 입 밖으로 내지 못하네♪
♪Knowing love and hate♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가 밀려와♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪차마 막을 수 없음을 알면서도♪
♪I still linger on♪
♪난 여전히 그대를 그리워하며♪
♪Unwilling to let go of every inch of our past♪
♪겹겹이 쌓인 지난날을 놓지 못하네♪
♪Last night's stars cast faint glimmers♪
♪어젯밤 하늘을 수놓던 아스라한 별빛♪
♪But we thought nothing of it♪
♪그때는 어찌 당연하게 여겼을까♪
♪With a heartbroken cry♪
♪가슴이 찢어지는 듯한 애달픈 외침으로♪
♪I wish you well♪
♪오직 그대의 안녕만을 바라네♪
♪Knowing right and wrong♪
♪옳고 그름도, 흑백의 경계도♪
♪Black and gray are all illusions♪
♪검고 흐린 세상사 모두 부질없거늘♪
♪You're still screaming♪
♪그대는 여전히 목 놓아 울부짖으며♪
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪미련 없이 거칠게 발버둥 치는구나♪
♪The storm looms, yet the wind stands in its way♪
♪몰아치는 비바람 온몸으로 막아서며♪
♪A final farewell left on the cliff♪
♪절벽 끝자락에 눈물로 새긴 서약♪
♪Leaping straight into♪
♪내 기꺼이 이 몸을 던지리라♪
♪That heartbreaking past♪
♪살을 도려내는 듯한 아픈 기억 속으로♪
♪Just to keep you safe♪
♪그대만 무사할 수 있다면♪
♪My breath is about to stop♪
♪내 숨결이 점차 희미해지고♪
♪Those hands can no longer hold yours♪
♪맞잡은 그 손을 더는 쥘 수 없으니♪
♪Through the future snow, wind, and fog♪
♪앞으로 다가올 시린 바람과 안개를♪
♪Who will be there by your side?♪
♪이제 누구와 함께 견뎌내야 할까♪
♪I smile as it ends♪
♪미소를 지으며 눈을 감는 것은♪
♪Afraid that you might cry for me♪
♪나로 인해 그대 슬피 울까 염려되어♪
♪Quietly, I turn into a sky lantern♪
♪말없이 공명등 한 줄기 빛이 되어♪
♪To light your way through the night♪
♪그대가 걷는 어두운 밤길을 비추어 주리♪
♪Knowing love and hate♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가 밀려와♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪차마 막을 수 없음을 알면서도♪
♪I still linger on♪
♪난 여전히 그대를 그리워하며♪
♪Unwilling to let go of every inch of our past♪
♪겹겹이 쌓인 지난날을 놓지 못하네♪
♪The storm looms, yet I stand in its way♪
♪닥쳐오는 비바람을 내 기어이 가로막으리♪
♪Torn inside, still I burn bright♪
♪가슴이 무너져 내릴지라도 참으로 감미롭구나♪
♪With the light from my fingertips♪
♪내 손끝에 맺힌 마지막 빛으로♪
♪I build a paradise♪
♪그대와 함께할 낙원을 세워♪
♪To wander with you♪
♪영원히 그대 곁을 거닐고 싶어라♪